[
    {
        "id": "lord_of_the_flies_publish",
        "text": "According to <a href=\"https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lord_of_the_Flies\">Wikipedia</a>.",
        "question": "In what year was Lord of the Flies published?",
        "answer": "1954",
        "range1": "\u00b1 2 years",
        "range2": "\u00b1 5 years",
        "range3": "\u00b1 10 years",
        "interval1": "1952 - 1956",
        "interval2": "1949 - 1959",
        "interval3": "1944 - 1964"
    },
    {
        "id": "pop_mexico",
        "text": "Estimated population in 2023 according to the CIA's <a href=\"https://www.cia.gov/the-world-factbook/countries/mexico/#people-and-society\">World Factbook</a>.",
        "question": "What is the population of Mexico as of 2023, in millions?",
        "answer": "130",
        "range1": "\u00b1 5%",
        "range2": "\u00b1 10%",
        "range3": "\u00b1 25%",
        "interval1": "123 - 137",
        "interval2": "117 - 143",
        "interval3": "97 - 163"
    },
    {
        "id": "louisiana_purchase",
        "text": "Date the purchase was established, according to <a href=\"https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Louisiana_Purchase\">Wikipedia</a>.  ",
        "question": "In what year did the Louisiana Purchase take place?",
        "answer": "1803",
        "range1": "\u00b1 3 years",
        "range2": "\u00b1 10 years",
        "range3": "\u00b1 30 years",
        "interval1": "1800 - 1806",
        "interval2": "1793 - 1813",
        "interval3": "1773 - 1833"
    },
    {
        "id": "wall-e_release",
        "text": "Date WALL-E was released to the United States, according to <a href=\"https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WALL-E\">Wikipedia</a>.",
        "question": "In what year was WALL-E released?",
        "answer": "2008",
        "range1": "\u00b1 0 years",
        "range2": "\u00b1 1 years",
        "range3": "\u00b1 3 years",
        "interval1": "2008",
        "interval2": "2007 - 2009",
        "interval3": "2005 - 2011"
    },
    {
        "id": "netflix_remote_button",
        "text": "From a <a href=\"https://www.howtogeek.com/54967/why-your-remote-has-dedicated-buttons-for-netflix-and-other-services/\"> 2020 article on howtogeek.com</a>: \"An article from Bloomberg Businessweek stated that \"Hulu, Netflix, Showtime, and YouTube have paid Roku to build brand-specific buttons on its remote controls; these lead users straight to those services. At <mark>$???</mark> per customer for each button, ...\" ",
        "question": "As of 2019, how much does Netflix pay TV company TCL to have a dedicated button on their TV remote? ",
        "answer": "$1",
        "range1": "factor of 2",
        "range2": "factor of 5",
        "range3": "factor of 10",
        "interval1": "$0.50 - $2",
        "interval2": "$0.20 - $5",
        "interval3": "$0.10 - $10"
    },
    {
        "id": "pearl_harbor_year",
        "text": "According to <a href=\"https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Attack_on_Pearl_Harbor\">Wikipedia</a>.  ",
        "question": "In what year did the attack on Pearl Harbor take place?",
        "answer": "1941",
        "range1": "\u00b1 0 years",
        "range2": "\u00b1 1 years",
        "range3": "\u00b1 2 years",
        "interval1": "1941",
        "interval2": "1940 - 1942",
        "interval3": "1939 - 1943"
    },
    {
        "id": "vehicle_fatality_ratio",
        "text": "Ratio of the value of \"Passenger cars\" to \"Motorcycles\" for the 2021 \"Fatality rate per 100 million vehicle miles traveled\" entry. Data from U.S. Department of Transportation, National Highway Traffic Safety Administration. Referenced from the <a href=\"https://www.iii.org/fact-statistic/facts-statistics-motorcycle-crashes\">Insurance Institute of America</a>. ",
        "question": "What is the ratio of motorcycle fatality to passenger car fatality per vehicle mile driven?",
        "answer": "24",
        "range1": "\u00b1 10%",
        "range2": "\u00b1 25%",
        "range3": "\u00b1 50%",
        "interval1": "21.6 - 26.4",
        "interval2": "18 - 30",
        "interval3": "12 - 36"
    },
    {
        "id": "nuclear_stockpile_year",
        "text": "According to Our World in Data, using the Federation of American Scientists as a source. Context provided by Our World in Data: The exact number of countries' warheads is secret, and the estimates are based on publicly available information, historical records, and occasional leaks. Warheads vary substantially in their power. <a href=\"\"https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/nuclear-warhead-stockpiles-lines\"\">Graph</a>.",
        "question": "In what year did the number of warheads in Russia's nuclear stockpile exceed the USA's?",
        "answer": "1978",
        "range1": "\u00b1 2 years",
        "range2": "\u00b1 5 years",
        "range3": "\u00b1 10 years",
        "interval1": "1976 - 1980",
        "interval2": "1973 - 1983",
        "interval3": "1968 - 1988"
    },
    {
        "id": "pixar_films",
        "text": "According to the <a href=\"https://www.pixar.com/feature-films-launch\">Feature Films section of the Pixar website</a>.",
        "question": "How many feature films has Pixar produced as of October 10, 2023?",
        "answer": "27",
        "range1": "\u00b1 5%",
        "range2": "\u00b1 10%",
        "range3": "\u00b1 25%",
        "interval1": "26 - 28",
        "interval2": "24 - 30",
        "interval3": "20 - 34"
    },
    {
        "id": "world_population_3billion_year",
        "text": "According to Our World in Data, using data published by United Nations, Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (2022). <a href=\"https://ourworldindata.org/explorers/population-and-demography?facet=none&country=~OWID_WRL&hideControls=false&Metric=Population&Sex=Both+sexes&Age+group=Total&Projection+Scenario=None\">Chart</a>. ",
        "question": "In what year did the world population first exceed 3 billion?",
        "answer": "1960",
        "range1": "\u00b1 5 years",
        "range2": "\u00b1 20 years",
        "range3": "\u00b1 50 years",
        "interval1": "1955 - 1965",
        "interval2": "1940 - 1980",
        "interval3": "1910 - 2010"
    },
    {
        "id": "japan_population_over65_fraction",
        "text": "According to Our World in Data, using data published by United Nations, Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (2022). De facto population in a country, area or region as of 1 July of the year indicated. <a href=\"https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/population-by-age-group?country=~JPN\">Chart</a>.",
        "question": "As of 2021, what fraction of the population of Japan is over 65?",
        "answer": "30%",
        "range1": "\u00b1 2 pp",
        "range2": "\u00b1 5 pp",
        "range3": "\u00b1 10 pp",
        "interval1": "28% - 32%",
        "interval2": "25% - 35%",
        "interval3": "20% - 40%"
    },
    {
        "id": "newborn_boys_to_girls_ratio",
        "text": "According to Our World in Data, using data published by United Nations, Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (2022). Number of males per 100 females in the population at birth. <a href=\"https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/sex-ratio-at-birth?country=~OWID_WRL\">Chart</a>.",
        "question": "As of 2021, globally, how many newborn boys are recorded for every 100 newborn girls?",
        "answer": "105.8",
        "range1": "\u00b1 1 boys",
        "range2": "\u00b1 2 boys",
        "range3": "\u00b1 3 boys",
        "interval1": "104.8 - 106.8",
        "interval2": "103.8 - 107.8",
        "interval3": "102.8 - 108.8"
    },
    {
        "id": "centenarians_gender_fraction",
        "text": "According to Our World in Data, using data published by United Nations, Department of Economic and Social Affairs, Population Division (2022). Number of males per 100 females in the population. <a href=\"https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/sex-ratio-by-age?facet=none\">Chart</a>.",
        "question": "As of 2021, globally, what fraction of people aged >100 are male?",
        "answer": "19%",
        "range1": "\u00b1 2 pp",
        "range2": "\u00b1 5 pp",
        "range3": "\u00b1 10 pp",
        "interval1": "17% - 21%",
        "interval2": "14% - 24%",
        "interval3": "9% - 29%"
    },
    {
        "id": "global_deaths_due_to_unsafe_sex_2019",
        "text": "According to <a href=\"https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/number-of-deaths-by-risk-factor\">Our World in Data</a> using data from the Global Burden of Disease published by the Institute of Health Metrics and Evaluation. <br><br>Unsafe sex is defined as the risk of disease due to sexual transmission. Unsafe sex is an important risk factor in cervical cancer, HIV and sexually-transmitted infections.",
        "question": "How many estimated deaths globally due to unsafe sex in 2019?",
        "answer": "984,366",
        "range1": "factor of 2",
        "range2": "factor of 5",
        "range3": "factor of 10",
        "interval1": "492,183 - 1,968,732",
        "interval2": "196,873 - 4,921,830",
        "interval3": "98,436 - 9,843,660"
    },
    {
        "id": "global_deaths_road_2019",
        "text": "According to <a href=\"https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/deaths-from-road-injuries?tab=chart&country=~OWID_WRL\">Our World in Data</a> using data from the World Health Organization. <br><br>Annual number of deaths from road injuries. Road injuries include deaths of drivers, passengers, pedestrians and cyclists.",
        "question": "How many estimated deaths globally due to road injuries in 2019?",
        "answer": "1280000",
        "range1": "factor of 2",
        "range2": "factor of 5",
        "range3": "factor of 10",
        "interval1": "640,000 - 2,560,000",
        "interval2": "256,000 - 6,400,000",
        "interval3": "128,000 - 12,800,000"
    },
    {
        "id": "global_deaths_venomous_animal_2019",
        "text": "According to <a href=\"https://ourworldindata.org/grapher/deaths-from-venomous-animal-contact?tab=chart&country=~OWID_WRL\">Our World in Data</a> using data from the Global Burden of Disease published by the Institute of Health Metrics and Evaluation.  <br><br>Annual number of deaths resulting from unintentionally being bitten by, stung by, or exposed to a venomous animal.",
        "question": "How many estimated deaths globally due to venomous animal contact in 2019?",
        "answer": "79741",
        "range1": "factor of 2",
        "range2": "factor of 5",
        "range3": "factor of 10",
        "interval1": "39,870 - 159,482",
        "interval2": "15,948 - 398,705",
        "interval3": "7,974 - 797,410"
    },
    {
        "id": "great_wall_of_china_length",
        "text": "According to the Wikipedia article <a href=\"https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Great_Wall_of_China\">Great Wall of China</a>. <br><br>Additional context from the article: <br>The Great Wall of China is a series of fortifications that were built across the historical northern borders of ancient Chinese states and Imperial China as protection against various nomadic groups from the Eurasian Steppe. Several walls were built from as early as the 7th century BC, with selective stretches later joined by Qin Shi Huang (220-206 BC), the first emperor of China. Little of the Qin wall remains. Later on, many successive dynasties built and maintained multiple stretches of border walls. The best-known sections of the wall were built by the Ming dynasty (1368-1644).<br>Apart from defense, other purposes of the Great Wall have included border controls, allowing the imposition of duties on goods transported along the Silk Road, regulation or encouragement of trade and the control of immigration and emigration. Furthermore, the defensive characteristics of the Great Wall were enhanced by the construction of watchtowers, troop barracks, garrison stations, signaling capabilities through the means of smoke or fire, and the fact that the path of the Great Wall also served as a transportation corridor.<br>The frontier walls built by different dynasties have multiple courses. Collectively, they stretch from Liaodong in the east to Lop Lake in the west, from the present-day Sino-Russian border in the north to Tao River (Taohe) in the south; along an arc that roughly delineates the edge of the Mongolian steppe; spanning <mark>???</mark> km (xxx mi) in total. Today, the defensive system of the Great Wall is generally recognized as one of the most impressive architectural feats in history.",
        "question": "What is the total length of the Great Wall of China, in kilometers?",
        "answer": "21196",
        "range1": "\u00b1 10%",
        "range2": "\u00b1 25%",
        "range3": "\u00b1 50%",
        "interval1": "19,076 - 23,316",
        "interval2": "15,897 - 26,495",
        "interval3": "10,598 - 31,794"
    },
    {
        "id": "operational_satellites_2021",
        "text": "According to the Wikipedia article <a href=\"https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Satellite\">Satellite</a>. <br><br>Additional context from the article: <br> <br>A satellite or artificial satellite is an object intentionally placed into orbit around a celestial body. Satellites have a variety of uses, including communication relay, weather forecasting, navigation (GPS), broadcasting, scientific research, and Earth observation. Additional military uses are reconnaissance, early warning, signals intelligence and, potentially, weapon delivery. Other satellites include the final rocket stages that place satellites in orbit and formerly useful satellites that later become defunct.<br>Except for passive satellites, most satellites have an electricity generation system for equipment on board, such as solar panels or radioisotope thermoelectric generators (RTGs). Most satellites also have a method of communication to ground stations, called transponders. Many satellites use a standardized bus to save cost and work, the most popular of which is a small CubeSats. Similar satellites can work together as groups, forming constellations. Because of the high launch cost to space, satellites are designed to be as lightweight and robust as possible. Most communication satellites are radio relay stations in orbit and carry dozens of transponders, each with a bandwidth of tens of megahertz.<br> <br>Satellites are placed from the surface to the orbit by launch vehicles, high enough to avoid orbital decay by the atmosphere. Satellites can then change or maintain the orbit by propulsion, usually by chemical or ion thrusters. As of 2018, about 90% of the satellites orbiting the Earth are in low Earth orbit or geostationary orbit; geostationary means the satellites stay still in the sky. Some imaging satellites chose a Sun-synchronous orbit because they can scan the entire globe with similar lighting. As the number of satellites and space debris around Earth increases, the threat of collision has become more severe. A small number of satellites orbit other bodies (such as the Moon, Mars, and the Sun) or many bodies at once (two for a halo orbit, three for a Lissajous orbit).<br> <br>Earth observation satellites gather information for reconnaissance, mapping, monitoring the weather, ocean, forest, etc. Space telescopes take advantage of outer space's near perfect vacuum to observe objects with the entire electromagnetic spectrum. Because satellites can see a large portion of the Earth at once, communications satellites can relay information to remote places. The signal delay from satellites and their orbit's predictability are used in satellite navigation systems, such as GPS. Space probes are satellites designed for robotic space exploration outside of Earth, and space stations are in essence crewed satellites.<br> <br>The first artificial satellite launched into the Earth's orbit was the Soviet Union's Sputnik 1, on October 4, 1957. As of December 31st 2022, there are <mark>???</mark> operational satellites in the Earth's orbit, of which xxx belong to the United States (xxx commercial), xxx belong to China, xxx belong to Russia, and xxx belong to other nations",
        "question": "As of December 31 2022, how many operational satellites are in Earth's orbit?",
        "answer": "6718",
        "range1": "factor of 2",
        "range2": "factor of 5",
        "range3": "factor of 10",
        "interval1": "3,359 - 13,436",
        "interval2": "1,343 - 33,590",
        "interval3": "671 - 67,180"
    },
    {
        "id": "mount_everest_height",
        "text": "According to the Wikipedia article <a href=\"https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mount_Everest\">Mount Everest</a>. <br><br>Based on the 2020 surveys of elevation of snow cap, not rock head.",
        "question": "What is the elevation of Mount Everest, in meters?",
        "answer": "8849",
        "range1": "\u00b1 2%",
        "range2": "\u00b1 5%",
        "range3": "\u00b1 10%",
        "interval1": "8,672 - 9,025",
        "interval2": "8,406 - 9,292",
        "interval3": "7,964 - 9,734"
    },
    {
        "id": "highest_recorded_earth_temperature",
        "text": "According to the Wikipedia article <a href=\"https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Highest_temperature_recorded_on_Earth\">Highest temperature recorded on Earth</a>. <br><br>Additional context, from the Wikipedia article: <br>The highest temperature recorded on Earth has been measured in three major ways: air, ground, and via satellite observation. Air measurements are used as the standard measurement due to persistent issues with unreliable ground and satellite readings. Air measurements are noted by the World Meteorological Organization (WMO) and Guinness World Records among others as the standard to be used for determining the official record. The current official highest registered air temperature on Earth is <mark>???</mark> \u00b0C (xxx \u00b0F), recorded on 10 July 1913 at Furnace Creek Ranch, in Death Valley in the United States.[1] For ninety years, a former record that was measured in Libya had been in place, until it was decertified in 2012 based on evidence that it was an erroneous reading. This finding has since raised questions about the legitimacy of the 1913 record measured in Death Valley, with several meteorological experts asserting that there were similar irregularities. The WMO has stood by the record as official pending any future investigative results. If the current record were to be decertified then the holder would be a tie at xxx \u00b0C (xxx \u00b0F), recorded both at Furnace Creek and in Kuwait.[a]Several unverified temperatures that exceed the current record have also been recorded. These include historical claims that were never authenticated due to the equipment available at the time and unverified scientific claims. There are also disproven amateur readings that have been posted on social media showing evidence of extreme temperature.",
        "question": "What is the highest recorded air temperature on Earth, in degrees Celsius?",
        "answer": "56.7",
        "range1": "\u00b1 1 C",
        "range2": "\u00b1 2 C",
        "range3": "\u00b1 3 C",
        "interval1": "55.7 - 57.7",
        "interval2": "54.7 - 58.7",
        "interval3": "53.7 - 59.7"
    },
    {
        "id": "landlocked_countries",
        "text": "According to the Wikipedia article <a href=\"https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Landlocked_country\">Landlocked country</a>.",
        "question": "As of 2023, how many countries are landlocked?",
        "answer": "44",
        "range1": "\u00b1 10%",
        "range2": "\u00b1 25%",
        "range3": "\u00b1 50%",
        "interval1": "39 - 49",
        "interval2": "33 - 55",
        "interval3": "22 - 66"
    },
    {
        "id": "apple_inc_employees",
        "text": "According to <a href=\"https://www.macrotrends.net/stocks/charts/AAPL/apple/number-of-employees\">macrotrends.net</a>. Number of employees on 9/30/2022.",
        "question": "As of 2021, how many people are employed by Apple Inc.?",
        "answer": "164000",
        "range1": "\u00b1 10%",
        "range2": "\u00b1 25%",
        "range3": "\u00b1 50%",
        "interval1": "147,600 - 180,400",
        "interval2": "123,000 - 205,000",
        "interval3": ""
    },
    {
        "id": "us_national_parks_count",
        "text": "According to the Wikipedia page for <a href=\"https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_national_parks_of_the_United_States\">List of national parks of the United States</a>.<br><br>More context from article:<br>The United States has ??? national parks, which are congressionally designated protected areas operated by the National Park Service, an agency of the Department of the Interior. National parks are designated for their natural beauty, unique geological features, diverse ecosystems, and recreational opportunities, typically \"because of some outstanding scenic feature or natural phenomena.\" While legislatively all units of the National Park System are considered equal with the same mission, national parks are generally larger and more of a destination, and hunting and extractive activities are prohibited. National monuments, on the other hand, are also frequently protected for their historical or archaeological significance. XXX national parks (including xxx in Alaska) are paired with a national preserve, areas with different levels of protection that are administered together but considered separate units and whose areas are not included in the figures below. The xxx units of the National Park System can be broadly referred to as national parks, but most have other formal designations.",
        "question": "What is the total number of National Parks in the United States?",
        "answer": "63",
        "range1": "\u00b1 5%",
        "range2": "\u00b1 10%",
        "range3": "\u00b1 25%",
        "interval1": "60 - 66",
        "interval2": "57 - 69",
        "interval3": "47 - 79"
    },
    {
        "id": "usa_gasoline_price_2021",
        "text": "According to <a href=\"https://fred.stlouisfed.org/series/GASREGCOVW#0\">FRED</a> data for US Regular Conventional Gas Price with data averaged yearly. <br><br>Weighted average based on sampling of approximately 900 retail outlets, 8:00AM Monday. The price represents self-service unless only full-service is available and includes all taxes. See (<a href=\"http://www.eia.doe.gov/oil_gas/petroleum/data_publications/wrgp/mogas_home_page.html\">http://www.eia.doe.gov/oil_gas/petroleum/data_publications/wrgp/mogas_home_page.html</a>) for further definitions. ",
        "question": "What is the average cost of a gallon of gasoline in the United States in 2019?",
        "answer": "2.5",
        "range1": "\u00b1 5%",
        "range2": "\u00b1 10%",
        "range3": "\u00b1 25%",
        "interval1": "2.375 - 2.625",
        "interval2": "2.25 - 2.75",
        "interval3": "1.875 - 3.125"
    },
    {
        "id": "trends_peak_diet_coke",
        "text": "According to <a href=\"https://trends.google.com/trends/explore?date=all&q=diet%20coke&hl=en\">Google Trends</a> for Worldwide data from 2004-2023. Trends data is presented monthly. This question is asking: In what year did the peak month occur?",
        "question": "In what year did the number of Google searches for \"diet coke\" peak?",
        "answer": "2006",
        "range1": "\u00b1 1 years",
        "range2": "\u00b1 3 years",
        "range3": "\u00b1 5 years",
        "interval1": "2005 - 2007",
        "interval2": "2003 - 2009",
        "interval3": "2001 - 2011"
    }
]